[whooshing sound effects]
[soft music plays]
[Gidon:] Many people ask me, what is the difference between
steam cleaning and dry cleaning methods.
Steam cleaning is basically extracting or washing your carpet
and extracting the dirt with a carpet cleaning machine back into a machine.
So, you're basically having...a process of wash,
they're getting down on your carpet where there is a detergent applied,
water applied, and then a suction appliedas well to extract the dirt out of your carpet.
With a dry cleaning system, all you do is spray detergent down
and go with an agitating machine with a pad to try and pick up as much dirt out of the carpet.
So, there is no extraction down the road.
It's basically just cleaning the toe part of the carpet
without going deep down into the bottom of the fibre.
The reason they created the dry cleaning system
is because steam cleaning used to take a lot longer to dry than the dry cleaning system.
A lot of people mistake the dry cleaning of carpets with dry cleaning of clothes,
but it's completely different methods.
Different detergents are getting used betweendry cleaning the carpet and dry cleaning clothes.
With dry cleaning clothes, you use solvents.
When you dry clean carpets, you use alkaline detergents,
you would use the dry cleaning process in the maintenance system
where you steam clean the carpet once ayear and then dry clean the carpet once a month.
I would only recommend using the dry cleaning system in a commercial job
and not in a residential job.
We do use the steam cleaning methodbecause it is a better method to clean your carpets.
[music plays]
[Captioning services provided by amara.org]